Menu burger Close thin Facebook Twitter Google plus Linked in Reddit Email arrow-right-sm arrow-right

Loading

    Calculators

    Mortgage Lender Reviews

    Compare Rates

    Helpful Guides

    Learn More

    Calculators

    Helpful Guides

    Tax Software Reviews

    Learn More

    Calculators

    Helpful Guides

    Learn More

    Find a Financial Advisor

    Firm Reviews

    Helpful Guides

    Financial Advisor Resources

    Learn More

    Calculators

    Compare Accounts

    Helpful Guides

    Banking Products

    Bank Reviews

    Personal Finance Resources

    Learn More

    Calculators

    Helpful Guides

    Compare Accounts

    Learn More

* More
    
    Credit Cards
    
    Best Credit Cards

    Helpful Guides

    Compare Cards

    Life Insurance
    
    Calculators

    Compare Quotes

    Helpful Guides

    Refinance
    
    Calculators

    Compare Rates

    Helpful Guides

    Personal Loans
    
    Calculators

    Compare Rates

    Helpful Guides

    Student Loans
    
    Calculators

    Compare Rates

    Helpful Guides

Search     

Tap on the profile icon to edit  
your financial details.  
Got It

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective date: December 31, 2019

**FINANCIAL INSIGHT TECHNOLOGY, INC** ("**Company**") is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe to you our practices regarding the personal data (as defined below) we collect from users of our website, located at www.SmartAsset.com (the "**Site**") and related services (collectively, "**Services**").  
  
**1\. USER CONSENT.** By submitting personal data through our Site and Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
  
**2\. A NOTE ABOUT CHILDREN.** We do not intentionally gather personal data about visitors who are under the age of 13.  
  
**3\. A NOTE TO USERS OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES.** Your personal data may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of personal data may be less stringent than the laws in your country. **BY USING OUR SITE OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL DATA THROUGH OUR SITE OR SERVICES, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**  
  
**4\. TYPES OF DATA WE COLLECT.**  
**Personal Data You Provide to Us.** We collect personal data from you when you **provide it voluntarily on the Site.** You may provide your name, phone number, email address, zip code, marital status, financial goals, household income, home ownership status, details about your family, Twitter handle, Facebook profile and other details you may submit to us. You may also provide information in response to our surveys,  
  
**Personal Data Collected via Technology.** To make our Site and Services more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect personal data from you, including **your IP address or HTTP referrer.** We also use Cookies (as defined below) and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the solutions and information for which you searched and which you viewed. Like most Internet services, we automatically gather this personal data and store it in log files each time you visit our website or access your account on our network.  
We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our website. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of our website may not work properly. We have also enabled Google Analytics features, including Demographics and Interest Reporting to gather demographic information provided by these features. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads by changing your Google Ads Settings.  
  
SmartAsset is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) self-regulatory program and adheres to the DAA self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. We work with a variety of advertisers, ad networks and analytics companies (“Ad Partners”) that collect information about your use of our services. You can opt out of the use of interest-based advertising at any time by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance consumer choice page.](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN#!%2F)  
  
**Our Relationship with Social Networking Sites.** We have created, and may offer you, interfaces that allow you to connect with social networking websites such as Facebook and Twitter ("SN Sites") through our Site. We will work with the SN Site's application protocol interface (better known as their developer API) in a way that allows you to authorize us to access your account on that SN Site on your behalf. In order to provide this authorization, you will not provide us with your user name or password to the SN Site, but you will need to log-in to that SN Site directly through our Site. Once authorized by you, the SN Site will provide us a token that allows the SN Site to recognize us when we ask, on your behalf, for access to your account information or to post information. You will be able to revoke our access to any SN Site at any time by amending the appropriate settings from within your account settings on the applicable SN Site, though such revocation may limit the Services we are able to provide you.  

**5\. USE OF YOUR DATA.**  
  
**General Use.** In general, personal data you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. Company uses your personal data in the following ways:

* Provide you with the Services and customer support;
* Respond to your requests, resolve disputes and/or troubleshoot problems;
* Verify your compliance with your obligations in our Terms of Use or other policies;
* Improve the quality of the Site and the Services;
* Communicate with you about the Site and the Services;
* Market our Services (and those of third parties) to you that we believe may be of interest to you. If you prefer that we do not send you these messages, please see the section below on **YOUR CHOICES REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL DATA** to learn how to opt-out.

Compliance and Protection. We may use your personal information to:  

* Comply with applicable laws, lawful requests, and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities;
* Protect our, your or others’ rights, privacy, safety or property (including by making and defending legal claims);
* Audit our internal processes for compliance with legal and contractual requirements and internal policies;
* Enforce the terms and conditions that govern the Site and the Services; and
* Prevent, identify, investigate and deter fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity, including cyberattacks and identity theft.

**Creation of Anonymous Data.** We may create Anonymous Data records from personal data by excluding information (such as your name) that make the data personally identifiable to you. We use this Anonymous Data to analyze request and usage patterns so that we may enhance the content of our Products and services and improve site navigation. Company reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Data to Third Party Companies in its discretion.  
  
**Feedback.** If you provide feedback on the Site or Services to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we will not associate such feedback with your personal data. Company will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the personal data in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
  
**6\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA.**  
  
**Affiliates.** . Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, **"Affiliates"**), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your personal data with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires Company or our assets, that company will possess the personal data collected by it and us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal data as described in this Privacy Policy.  
  
**Disclosure to Third Party Service Providers.** We may share your personal data with third party service providers to facilitate creation of accounts or to provide services to us that enable us to make the Site or the Services available to you.  
  
**Disclosure to SmartAsset AMP Marketplace and Marketing Participants.** We may share your advisor matching form intake data with relevant financial advisor matches that meet participation criteria and actively participate in the SmartAsset AMP platform. The terms and conditions permit those advisors to contact you with the information you have provided.  
  
**Other Disclosures.** Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal data (as described below), Company may disclose personal data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Company; or (b) protect or defend the rights or property of Company or users of the Products or related services.  
  
**7\. THIRD PARTIES.**  
  
Personal and/or Anonymous Data Collected by Third Parties. We may receive Personal and/or Anonymous Data about you from other sources like telephone or fax, or from companies that provide our Services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website or companies that offer their products and/or services on our website ("Third Party Companies"). Our Third Party Companies may supply us with personal data, such as your email address, in order to help us establish the account. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our website in order to improve the Services we provide.  
  
Our provision of a link to any other website or location, such as the payment processing websites, is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. When you click on such a link, you will leave our site and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect personal data or Anonymous Data from you.  
  
We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on links to such outside websites.  
  
**NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS - YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS (AS PROVIDED BY CALIFORNIA CIVIL CODE SECTION 1798.83).  
  
A CALIFORNIA RESIDENT WHO HAS PROVIDED PERSONAL DATA TO A BUSINESS WITH WHOM HE/SHE HAS ESTABLISHED A BUSINESS RELATIONSHIP FOR PERSONAL, FAMILY, OR HOUSEHOLD PURPOSES (A "CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER"), MAY REQUEST INFORMATION ABOUT WHETHER THE BUSINESS HAS DISCLOSED PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY THIRD PARTIES FOR THE THIRD PARTIES' DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES. IN GENERAL, IF THE BUSINESS HAS MADE SUCH A DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA, UPON RECEIPT OF A REQUEST BY A CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER, THE BUSINESS IS REQUIRED TO PROVIDE A LIST OF ALL THIRD PARTIES TO WHOM PERSONAL DATA WAS DISCLOSED IN THE PRECEDING CALENDAR YEAR, AS WELL AS A LIST OF THE CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA THAT WERE DISCLOSED. CALIFORNIA CUSTOMERS MAY REQUEST FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT OUR COMPLIANCE WITH THIS LAW BY E-MAILING INFO@SMARTASSET.COM. PLEASE NOTE THAT WE ARE REQUIRED TO RESPOND TO ONE REQUEST PER CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER EACH YEAR, AND WE ARE NOT REQUIRED TO RESPOND TO REQUESTS MADE BY MEANS OTHER THAN THROUGH THIS E-MAIL ADDRESS.**  
  
**8\. YOUR CHOICES REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL DATA.**  
  
**Choices.** . We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your personal data. We will periodically send you free newsletters and e-mails that directly promote the use of our site or the purchase of our Services and may contain advertisements for Third Party Companies. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). Should you decide to opt- out of receiving future mailings, we may share your e-mail address with third parties to ensure that you do not receive further communications from third parties. Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you notices of any updates to our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy.  
  
**Changes to Personal Data.** You may request deletion of your personal data by us, but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives.  
  
**9\. JOB APPLICANTS.** When visit the careers portion of our Sites, we collect the information that you provide to us in connection with your job application. This includes business and personal contact information, professional credentials and skills, educational and work history, and other information of the type that may be included in a resume. This may also include diversity information that you voluntarily provide. We use this information to facilitate our recruitment activities and process employment applications, such as by evaluating a job candidate for an employment activity, and monitoring recruitment statistics. We may also use this information to operate and improve the Services, and as otherwise necessary for compliance, fraud prevention, and safety purposes.  
  
**10\. SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA.** Company is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Despite these measures, you should know that Company cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with personal data and mistakes may happen.  
  
**11\. CONTACT INFORMATION.** The company welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [info@smartasset.com](mailto:info@smartasset.com) or contact us at the following address:  
  
**Financial Insight Technology, Inc  
Attn: Michael Carvin  
122 East 42nd Street, Suite 4300, New York, NY 10168, USA  
**  
  
**12\. DISPUTE RESOLUTION.** If you believe that Company has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Company by email at info@smartasset.com. We will do our best to address your concerns. If you feel that your complaint has been addressed incompletely, we invite you to let us know for further investigation.  
  
**13\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.** This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal data, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail to the last e-mail address you provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our site. These changes will be effective immediately for new users of our website, Products or related services. Please note that at all times you are responsible for updating your personal data to provide us with your most current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of personal data that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your personal data, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your account with us. Continued use of our website, Products, or related services, following notice of such changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.  
  
**14\. NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**  
We are required by the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“**CCPA**”) to provide to California residents an explanation of how we collect, use and share their personal Information, and of the rights and choices we offer California residents regarding our handling of their personal information. CCPA Scope and Exclusions. The description of our [Privacy Practices](#privacy_practices) and [Privacy Rights](#privacy_rights) in this Notice apply only to California residents whose interactions with SmartAsset are limited to:

* Visiting our website,
* Signing up for email alerts,
* Commenting on or contributing to our forums, or
* Applying for our job openings on our websites (however, the CCPA does not extend [Privacy Rights](#privacy_rights) to job applicants).

The description of our [Privacy Practices](#privacy_practices) and CCPA Privacy Rights do not apply to the personal information we collect, use or disclose about:  

* Consumers who initiate or complete the process of applying for financial products or services. This is because this information is subject to the federal Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (“GLBA”), and implementing regulations, or the California Financial Information Privacy Act (“FIPA”), and
* Representatives of businesses that seek to obtain our Services, or to provide their products or services to us.

**Privacy Practices.** We do not sell personal information. As we explain in our [Privacy Policy](#privacy_policy):

* We use cookies and other tracking technologies to analyze website traffic and facilitate advertising. If you would like to learn how you may opt out of our (and our third party advertising partners’) use of cookies and other tracking technologies, please review the instructions provided in the [Online Tracking Opt-out Guide](#opt_out).
* Through our services – for example, by inquiring about retaining a financial advisor – you direct us to disclose your information to companies that provide the services in which you are interested.

Here is a description of our relevant privacy practices:  

| How you interact with us | Personal information collection | CCPA-defined categories | Sources of personal information | Purposes for which we may collect and use the personal information | Data Sharing |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| * **Sign up for email alerts**<br>* **Interact with our blogs and forums**<br>* **Establish an account** | * Name or alias<br>* Email address | * Identifiers | * You | * Operations<br>* Communications<br>* Research and development<br>* Marketing | * Shared with service providers<br>* Made public at your direction |
| * **Visit our websites**<br>* **Receive and Respond to marketing emails** | * Device data<br>* Online activity data<br>* Information derived from device data and online activity data | * Identifiers<br>* Inferences<br>* Internet or Network Information<br>* Online Identifiers | * Automatic collection | * Operations<br>* Communications<br>* Marketing<br>* Advertising<br>* Research and development | * Collected directly by or shared with our service providers<br>* Collected directly by advertising partners |
| * **Apply for our open positions on our website** | * Contact information<br>* Professional credentials and skills<br>* Educational and work history<br>* Other resume data you provide<br>* Diversity information you voluntarily provide<br>* Disability information where necessary | * Identifiers<br>* Online identifiers<br>* Education information<br>* Professional or employment information<br>* Protected classification characteristics | * You<br>* References<br>* Background check and/or drug testing companies<br>* Employment agencies or recruiters | * Facilitate recruitment activities<br>* Process employment applications<br>* Monitoring recruitment statistics | * Shared with service providers<br>* Collected directly by or shared with background check and drug testing companies |

Please note that we may also disclose personal information to comply with law, and for compliance, fraud prevention, and safety purposes; in the event of business transfers; and to our professional advisors, as further described above in the Privacy Policy.  
  
**The CCPA grants individuals the following rights:**

* Information. You can request information about how we have collected, used and shared your Personal Information during the past 12 months.
* Access. You can request a copy of the personal information that we maintain about you.
* Deletion. You can ask us to delete the personal information that we collected or maintain about you.

Please note that the CCPA limits these rights by, for example, prohibiting us from providing certain sensitive information in response to an access request and limiting the circumstances in which we must comply with a deletion request. We will also respond to requests for information and access only to the extent we are able to associate with a reasonable effort the information we maintain with the identifying details you provide in your request. If we deny your request, we will communicate our decision to you.  
You are entitled to exercise the rights described above free from discrimination.  
  
**How to Submit a Request.** To request access to or deletion of personal information:

* email: info@smartasset.com

**Identity verification.** The CCPA requires us to verify the identity of the individual submitting a request to access or delete personal information before providing a substantive response to the request.  
**Authorized agents.** California residents can empower an “authorized agent” to submit requests on their behalf. We will require the authorized agent to have a written authorization confirming that authority.  
  
**Online Tracking Opt-Out Guide**

Like many companies online, we use services provided by Google, Facebook and others companies that use tracking technology. These services rely on tracking technologies – such as cookies and web beacons – to collect directly from your device information about your browsing activities, your interactions with websites, and the device you are using to connect to the Internet. There are a number of ways to opt out of having your online activity and device data collected through these services, which we have summarized below:

* **Blocking cookies in your browser.** Most browsers let you remove or reject cookies, including cookies used for interest-based advertising. To do this, follow the instructions in your browser settings. Many browsers accept cookies by default until you change your settings. For more information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
* **Blocking advertising ID use in your mobile settings.** Your mobile device settings may provide functionality to limit use of the advertising ID associated with your mobile device for interest-based advertising purposes.
* **Using privacy plug-ins or browsers.** You can block our websites from setting cookies used for interest-based ads by using a browser with privacy features, like [Brave](https://brave.com/), or installing browser plugins like [Privacy Badger](https://www.eff.org/privacybadger), [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/) or [uBlock Origin](https://ublock.org/), and configuring them to block third party cookies/trackers.
* **Platform opt-outs.** The following advertising partners offer opt-out features that let you opt-out of use of your information for interest-based advertising:
    * Google: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/)
    * Facebook: [https://www.facebook.com/about/ads](https://www.facebook.com/about/ads)
    * Twitter: [https://twitter.com/personalization](https://twitter.com/personalization)
* **Advertising industry opt-out tools.** You can also use these opt-out options to limit use of your information for interest-based advertising by participating companies:
    * Digital Advertising Alliance: [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/)
    * Network Advertising Initiative: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)

Get in touch [Contact](https://smartasset.com/about#contact) [Careers](https://smartasset.com/careers)

SmartAsset [Search](https://smartasset.com/search) [About](https://smartasset.com/about) [SmartReads](https://smartasset.com/blog) [Captivate](https://smartasset.com/captivate) [SmartAsset AMP](https://get.smartasset.com/advisor-marketing-platform) [Press](https://smartasset.com/press) [SmartAdvisorMatch](https://smartadvisormatch.com/)

Get Social[Like on Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/smartasset)[Follow on Twitter](https://twitter.com/smartasset)

Legal Stuff [Terms of Service](https://smartasset.com/terms) [Privacy Policy](https://smartasset.com/privacy) [AdChoices](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/) [GLB Notice](https://smartasset.com/glb-notice) [Online Tracking Opt-Out Guide](https://smartasset.com/privacy#opt_out)

SmartAsset Advisors, LLC ("SmartAsset"), a wholly owned subsidiary of Financial Insight Technology, is registered with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission as an investment adviser. SmartAsset’s services are limited to referring users to third party advisers registered or chartered as fiduciaries ("Adviser(s)") with a regulatory body in the United States that have elected to participate in our matching platform based on information gathered from users through our online questionnaire. SmartAsset receives compensation from Advisers for our services. SmartAsset does not review the ongoing performance of any Adviser, participate in the management of any user’s account by an Adviser or provide advice regarding specific investments. We do not manage client funds or hold custody of assets, we help users connect with relevant financial advisors. This is not an offer to buy or sell any security or interest. All investing involves risk, including loss of principal. Working with an adviser may come with potential downsides such as payment of fees (which will reduce returns). There are no guarantees that working with an adviser will yield positive returns. The existence of a fiduciary duty does not prevent the rise of potential conflicts of interest.

Smartly made in NYC

© 2024 SmartAsset, all rights reserved.

OK Cancel

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
|     | An error occurred Please reload the page. |
